Sahib Julka

 ${\it Machine \ Learning \ Scientist} \\ +49\ 1590\ 161\ 2115\ |\ sahib.julka@yahoo.com\ |\ \underline{Linkedin}\ |\ Google\ Scholar$

Summary

Creative problem solver with a strong background in Machine Learning domains such as Vision, Time-Series Signals, and Causal Inference. My PhD was on advancing Machine Learning tools in the application domains of Planetary Science. I have also worked actively towards making Representation Learning more controllable and interpretable, as well as contributed in Deep Active Learning.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python

Machine Learning Frameworks: PyTorch, Tensorflow, Scikit-Learn

Tools: MLOps, WandB, Git

EXPERIENCE

Research Associate Apr. 2018 – Dec 2024

University of Passau, Germany

- Led Machine Learning in Europe-wide project on Planetary Science viz. Europlanet2024
- $\bullet\,$ Taught Data Science Lab and Machine Learning Lab for 5 years
- Supervised numerous Masters and Bachelors Thesis
- Organised Hackathons and Convened Machine Learning Workshops/Conference Sessions

Student Researcher
Nov. 2017 – Jan 2018
University of Passau
Passau, Germany

• Developed Data Annotation tool

Machine Learning Engineer

Upwork.com

Aug. 2017 – Mar 2018

Passau, Germany

• Predictive modeling jobs

EDUCATION

PERSONAL DETAILS

Status: 32M, Single, German Citizen

Languages: English (First), German (Fluent)

Hobbies: Music, Sports, Photography